<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-02T09:01:16+00:00</updated><id>https://kilian-kleemann.info/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Immune Dysfunction in Alzheimer’s Disease — Our Latest Review in Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2025/immune-dysfunction-in-alzheimers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Immune Dysfunction in Alzheimer’s Disease — Our Latest Review in Nature Reviews Neuroscience"/><published>2025-11-29T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-29T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2025/immune-dysfunction-in-alzheimers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2025/immune-dysfunction-in-alzheimers/"><![CDATA[<p>In November 2025, our review <em>“Immune dysfunction in Alzheimer’s disease”</em> was published in <strong>Nature Reviews Neuroscience</strong>, where we synthesize the rapidly evolving understanding of how immunity contributes to Alzheimer’s disease (AD). This work brings together conceptual, mechanistic, and translational perspectives to outline how both peripheral and central immune pathways shape disease initiation and progression.</p> <p>I contributed to the <strong>conceptual development</strong>, <strong>manuscript formulation</strong>, <strong>writing</strong>, and the <strong>design and creation of several figures</strong> in the review, working closely with colleagues across neuroimmunology, genetics, and systems neuroscience.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="the-immune-system-as-a-driver-of-alzheimers-disease">The Immune System as a Driver of Alzheimer’s Disease</h2> <p>Alzheimer’s disease has long been understood through the lens of amyloid and tau pathology, yet these hallmarks interact deeply with the immune system. Our review highlights how:</p> <ul> <li>microglia integrate genetic risk with environmental and aging cues</li> <li>astrocytes, oligodendrocytes, and peripheral immune cells participate in maladaptive inflammatory loops</li> <li>T cells, cytokine environments, and innate immune sensors contribute to chronic neuroinflammation</li> <li>systemic immune aging reshapes brain homeostasis long before cognitive symptoms appear</li> </ul> <p>Rather than treating immunity as a downstream response, we argue that immune dysfunction <strong>actively shapes the trajectory of the disease</strong>.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="key-concepts-from-the-review">Key Concepts from the Review</h2> <h3 id="genetic-risk-converges-on-microglia"><strong>Genetic Risk Converges on Microglia</strong></h3> <p>Genes like <em>TREM2, CD33,</em> and <em>APOE4</em> point toward microglial dysfunction as a core disease mechanism. Many of these risk alleles regulate lipid handling, phagocytosis, nucleic acid sensing, and inflammatory signaling.</p> <h3 id="transposable-elements-and-nucleic-acid-sensing"><strong>Transposable Elements and Nucleic Acid Sensing</strong></h3> <p>A major conceptual theme is the recognition that endogenous nucleic acids—including those derived from transposable elements—can activate innate immune pathways. These interactions may contribute to chronic interferon signaling, synaptic dysfunction, and microglial state transitions in AD.</p> <h3 id="peripheral-immunity-matters"><strong>Peripheral Immunity Matters</strong></h3> <p>Growing evidence suggests that peripheral immune cells infiltrate the brain or influence neuroinflammation from the periphery. Dysregulation of monocytes, T cells, and inflammatory cytokines increasingly appears to be part of the disease cascade.</p> <h3 id="microglial-state-dynamics"><strong>Microglial State Dynamics</strong></h3> <p>We summarize emerging microglial subpopulations—including disease-associated microglia (DAM), interferon-response microglia (IRM/IEM), and lipid-associated states—that link molecular profiles to pathological stages.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="figures-clarifying-complexity-through-visual-integration">Figures: Clarifying Complexity Through Visual Integration</h2> <p>To help readers navigate this complex landscape, our review includes several integrative figures summarizing:</p> <ul> <li>the temporal evolution of immune dysfunction</li> <li>interactions between microglia, peripheral immune cells, and pathological proteins</li> <li>molecular pathways linking transposable elements, nucleic acid sensing, and interferon responses</li> <li>therapeutic strategies targeting immune pathways</li> </ul> <p>I designed and produced these figure panels to distill multi-layered findings into accessible visual overviews.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="looking-ahead-immune-pathways-as-therapeutic-gateways">Looking Ahead: Immune Pathways as Therapeutic Gateways</h2> <p>A key message of our review is that immune dysfunction is not merely a consequence of AD—it is a <strong>modifiable driver</strong>. Future interventions may target:</p> <ul> <li>microglial checkpoints</li> <li>interferon signaling</li> <li>TREM2 and lipid metabolism pathways</li> <li>peripheral immune modulation</li> <li>nucleic acid sensing and inflammation triggered by transposable elements</li> </ul> <p>Understanding these mechanisms offers a roadmap for next-generation therapies that intervene earlier and more precisely.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="read-the-full-article">Read the Full Article</h2> <p>You can read the full review here:<br/> <strong>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41583-025-00997-0</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="Alzheimer’s"/><category term="microglia"/><category term="immunity"/><category term="review"/><category term="NRN"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A perspective on our recent review exploring how innate and adaptive immune pathways shape the trajectory of Alzheimer’s disease.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microglial Checkpoint Regulation: TIM-3 Blockade Releases Protective Microglial States in Alzheimer’s Disease</title><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2025/tim3-microglia-alzheimers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microglial Checkpoint Regulation: TIM-3 Blockade Releases Protective Microglial States in Alzheimer’s Disease"/><published>2025-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2025/tim3-microglia-alzheimers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2025/tim3-microglia-alzheimers/"><![CDATA[<p>Alzheimer’s disease research is increasingly recognizing the central role of <strong>microglia</strong>, the brain’s resident immune cells, in shaping disease progression. In our recent <em>Nature</em> publication, we investigated how the immune checkpoint molecule <strong>TIM-3 (HAVCR2)</strong> regulates microglial function and constrains their ability to combat amyloid pathology.</p> <p>A major conceptual insight from this study is that <strong>blocking TIM-3 releases microglia from a homeostatic state</strong>, enabling them to enter a <strong>neuroprotective, plaque-clearing phenotype</strong> that slows Alzheimer’s pathology.</p> <p>I contributed to the <strong>single-cell RNA-seq</strong>, <strong>bulk RNA-seq processing</strong>, and <strong>transcriptomic analysis</strong> that uncovered the gene-expression programs underlying this shift.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="tim-3-as-a-microglial-checkpoint">TIM-3 as a Microglial Checkpoint</h2> <p>TIM-3 is well known for driving T-cell exhaustion, but its function in microglia has been poorly understood. Using biochemical and transcriptomic analyses<br/> :contentReference[oaicite:0]{index=0}, we show that:</p> <ul> <li><strong>TGFβ signalling induces TIM-3 expression</strong> in microglia.</li> <li>TIM-3 binds <strong>TGFBR2</strong> and <strong>SMAD2</strong>, enhancing SMAD2 phosphorylation.</li> <li>This interaction <strong>stabilizes a homeostatic microglial identity</strong>.</li> </ul> <p>When TIM-3 is present, microglia remain in a restrained state, limiting their ability to respond to pathological cues such as amyloid-β (Aβ).</p> <hr/> <h2 id="releasing-microglia-from-homeostasis-improves-alzheimers-pathology">Releasing Microglia from Homeostasis Improves Alzheimer’s Pathology</h2> <p>When <strong>Havcr2 (TIM-3)</strong> is selectively deleted in microglia:</p> <ul> <li>Microglia shift into a <strong>MGnD/DAM-like activation state</strong> with increased phagocytic gene expression</li> <li>Pro-inflammatory signalling programs (TNF, IFNα, cGAS–STING) are <strong>decoupled</strong> from phagocytosis</li> <li><strong>Amyloid plaque burden decreases significantly</strong></li> <li><strong>Cognitive performance improves</strong> in 5×FAD Alzheimer’s mouse models<br/> :contentReference[oaicite:1]{index=1}</li> </ul> <p>This demonstrates that TIM-3 acts as a <strong>molecular brake</strong> preventing microglia from entering a protective activation state. Its removal unleashes microglia to engage plaques more effectively and mitigate neurodegeneration.</p> <p>Importantly, TIM-3 expression is elevated in <strong>APOE4 carriers</strong>, particularly women, correlating with impaired MGnD activation—suggesting strong translational relevance.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="transcriptomic-profiling-reveals-the-mechanism">Transcriptomic Profiling Reveals the Mechanism</h2> <p>Using <strong>single-nucleus RNA-seq</strong>, <strong>single-cell RNA-seq</strong>, and <strong>bulk RNA-seq</strong>, we profiled how TIM-3 blockade remodels microglial states<br/> :contentReference[oaicite:2]{index=2} :contentReference[oaicite:3]{index=3}:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Phagosome and lysosomal pathways</strong> were upregulated across microglial clusters</li> <li>Neuroprotective signalling (<strong>PI3K–AKT–mTOR</strong>) increased</li> <li><strong>Homeostatic marker genes</strong> like <em>P2ry12</em>, <em>Csf1r</em>, and <em>Siglech</em> were downregulated</li> <li><strong>MGnD gene signatures</strong> were strongly enhanced</li> <li>Hypoxia signatures—associated with dysfunctional AD microglia—were reduced</li> </ul> <p>These multi-omics findings support a model in which TIM-3 normally maintains homeostasis via TGFβ signalling. Removing TIM-3 <strong>releases microglia into a protective, anti-inflammatory, pro-phagocytic state</strong> that is unusually effective at controlling plaque accumulation.</p> <p><strong>My role:</strong> I contributed to the computational analysis of both <strong>single-cell</strong> and <strong>bulk transcriptomic datasets</strong>, including quality control, differential gene expression, cluster-level scoring, and visualization of microglial state transitions.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="therapeutic-implications">Therapeutic Implications</h2> <p>Because <strong>HAVCR2 is expressed specifically in microglia within the CNS</strong>, targeting TIM-3 may allow:</p> <ul> <li>selective microglial reprogramming</li> <li>enhanced plaque clearance</li> <li>reduced inflammatory toxicity</li> <li>minimal systemic immune side effects</li> </ul> <p>This positions TIM-3 as an attractive therapeutic target—especially for patient subgroups with impaired microglial activation, such as <strong>APOE4 carriers</strong>.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="read-the-full-publication">Read the Full Publication</h2> <p><strong>Immune checkpoint TIM-3 regulates microglia and Alzheimer’s disease</strong><br/> <em>Nature</em> (2025)<br/> https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-08852-z</p> <hr/> <p>If you would like an extended “Behind the Paper” section, an infographic summary, or integrated figure panels for this blog post, I can generate those as well.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="microglia"/><category term="Alzheimer"/><category term="immunity"/><category term="TIM3"/><category term="HAVCR2"/><category term="single-cell"/><category term="RNA-seq"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blocking the immune checkpoint TIM-3 releases microglia from homeostatic restraint, enhances plaque clearance, and improves cognition in Alzheimer’s disease models.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">APOE4 Shapes Neutrophil–Microglia Crosstalk in Alzheimer’s Disease: My First-Author Work in Nature Medicine</title><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2024/apoe4-neutrophils-microglia-natmed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="APOE4 Shapes Neutrophil–Microglia Crosstalk in Alzheimer’s Disease: My First-Author Work in Nature Medicine"/><published>2024-07-01T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2024/apoe4-neutrophils-microglia-natmed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2024/apoe4-neutrophils-microglia-natmed/"><![CDATA[<p>I am excited to share a deeper look into my <strong>shared first-author</strong> publication in <em>Nature Medicine</em>, a project that grew out of my <strong>Master’s thesis</strong> and went on to become one of the cornerstone studies of my early research career. In this work, we investigated how the Alzheimer’s disease risk gene <strong>APOE4</strong> drives dysregulated communication between <strong>neutrophils</strong> and <strong>microglia</strong>, ultimately contributing to cognitive decline.</p> <p>My contributions included <strong>all computational data analysis</strong>, spanning bulk and single-cell RNA-seq, machine-learning modeling, biomarker discovery, and transcriptomic integration. I also <strong>wrote large portions of the manuscript</strong>, and <strong>designed, organized, and produced the figures</strong> that present the central concepts of the study.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="background-apoe4-as-an-immune-risk-gene">Background: APOE4 as an Immune Risk Gene</h2> <p>APOE4 is the strongest genetic risk factor for late-onset Alzheimer’s disease. While traditionally viewed through the lens of lipid metabolism and amyloid biology, increasing evidence suggests that <strong>APOE4 reshapes immune function</strong>, both in the central nervous system and the periphery.</p> <p>Our study reveals that APOE4 disrupts immune homeostasis by altering the behaviour of <strong>neutrophils</strong>, which in turn affects microglial activation states in the brain. According to the model and schematics in the paper <em>(see illustrated immune cascade on pg. 2 of the PDF)</em>, APOE4 drives a heightened innate immune tone that primes microglia toward dysfunctional activation during AD progression.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="a-machine-learning-discovery-il18r1-neutrophils-as-a-biomarker">A Machine-Learning Discovery: IL18R1+ Neutrophils as a Biomarker</h2> <p><em>(derived from transcriptomics and ML classification — see heatmap and feature-selection analysis on pg. 7)</em></p> <p>A central part of my master’s thesis was the application of <strong>machine learning</strong> to peripheral immune data to discover cell populations and molecular signatures associated with APOE4.</p> <p>Using:</p> <ul> <li>feature selection methods</li> <li>classification algorithms</li> <li>transcriptomic integration across datasets</li> <li>dimensionality reduction and clustering</li> <li>pathway enrichment</li> </ul> <p>I identified a subset of <strong>IL18R1-positive neutrophils</strong> that were <strong>pronounced in APOE4 carriers</strong>, especially in women, mirroring the sex- and genotype-specific patterns seen in microglial dysfunction.</p> <p>These IL18R1+ neutrophils displayed:</p> <ul> <li>pro-inflammatory signatures</li> <li>altered chemokine receptor landscapes</li> <li>associations with cognitive impairment scores</li> <li>transcriptional alignment with disease-associated microglia (DAM/MGnD signatures)</li> </ul> <p>This finding is highlighted as a <strong>potential peripheral biomarker</strong>, offering a window into CNS immune dysfunction through accessible blood measurements.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="microglia-reflect-neutrophil-dysregulation">Microglia Reflect Neutrophil Dysregulation</h2> <p><em>(see microglial single-cell UMAP and pathway overlays on pg. 4)</em></p> <p>Our analysis revealed that APOE4 disrupts not only peripheral immunity but also central microglial states. The transcriptomic maps show:</p> <ul> <li>increased <strong>IFN-response microglia (IRM/IEM)</strong></li> <li>dysregulated lipid metabolism</li> <li>impaired transition into beneficial phagocytic states</li> <li>elevated inflammatory tone in women carrying APOE4</li> </ul> <p>This immune axis — from blood neutrophils to brain microglia — underscores a multi-system nature of AD risk.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="what-makes-il18r1-neutrophils-a-promising-biomarker">What Makes IL18R1+ Neutrophils a Promising Biomarker?</h2> <p>From the combined machine-learning and RNA-seq analyses:</p> <ul> <li><strong>IL18R1 expression robustly discriminated APOE4 carriers</strong></li> <li>It correlated with microglial activation states in brain tissue</li> <li>It was detectable in peripheral blood, making clinical translation feasible</li> <li>It captured sex-dependent immune variation, which may refine risk stratification</li> </ul> <p>This discovery offers a novel bridge between <strong>peripheral diagnostics</strong> and <strong>central immune pathology</strong> in Alzheimer’s disease.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="my-contributions-to-the-study">My Contributions to the Study</h2> <p>This project was deeply meaningful to me, both scientifically and personally. My key contributions included:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Shared first authorship</strong></li> <li><strong>Full computational analysis</strong>, including: <ul> <li>bulk RNA-seq</li> <li>single-cell RNA-seq</li> <li>clustering, DEG analysis, pathway analysis</li> <li>machine learning for biomarker discovery</li> <li>integration of neutrophil and microglial datasets</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Conceptual development and model building</strong></li> <li><strong>Manuscript writing</strong>, including drafting several key sections</li> <li><strong>Designing and producing the figures</strong>, including the multi-layered immune interaction diagrams</li> <li><strong>Data interpretation</strong>, helping shape the narrative that connects APOE4, neutrophils, and microglia</li> </ul> <p>This publication played a formative role in shaping the direction of my PhD work on neuroimmune regulation and transposable element biology.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="a-step-toward-immune-based-precision-medicine-in-alzheimers">A Step Toward Immune-Based Precision Medicine in Alzheimer’s</h2> <p>By identifying a <strong>sex- and genotype-specific immune signature</strong> and mapping its influence from the periphery to the brain, this study opens the door toward future:</p> <ul> <li>blood-based biomarkers</li> <li>stratified clinical trials</li> <li>targeted immunomodulatory therapies</li> </ul> <p>Our findings highlight that Alzheimer’s disease is not only a disorder of neurons and protein aggregates but also of <strong>immune communication</strong>—and that intervening in these pathways may offer entirely new treatment strategies.</p> <hr/> <p>If you would like to read the full article or learn more about the data analyses behind the study, feel free to reach out. A more detailed technical breakdown of the machine-learning pipeline will be posted soon.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="research"/><category term="Alzheimer"/><category term="microglia"/><category term="neutrophils"/><category term="APOE4"/><category term="machine-learning"/><category term="biomarker"/><category term="transcriptomics"/><category term="Nature-Medicine"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My shared first-author publication identifying IL18R1+ neutrophils as potential biomarkers in APOE4-driven immune dysregulation in Alzheimer's disease.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[<p>Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:Learn more:May 14, 2024 We’re introducing a series of updates across the Gemini family of models, including the new 1.5 Flash, our lightweight model for speed and efficiency, and Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants. In December, we launched our first natively multimodal model Gemini 1.0 in three sizes: Ultra, Pro and Nano. Just a few months later we released 1.5 Pro, with enhanced performance and a breakthrough long context window of 1 million tokens.Developers and enterprise customers have been putting 1.5 Pro to use in incredible ways and finding its long context window, multimodal reasoning capabilities and impressive overall performance incredibly useful.We know from user feedback that some applications need lower latency and a lower cost to serve. This inspired us to keep innovating, so today, we’re introducing Gemini 1.5 Flash: a model that’s lighter-weight than 1.5 Pro, and designed to be fast and efficient to serve at scale.Both 1.5 Pro and 1.5 Flash are available in public preview with a 1 million token context window in Google AI Studio and Vertex AI. And now, 1.5 Pro is also available with a 2 million token context window via waitlist to developers using the API and to Google Cloud customers.We’re also introducing updates across the Gemini family of models, announcing our next generation of open models, Gemma 2, and sharing progress on the future of AI assistants, with Project Astra.Context lengths of leading foundation models compared with Gemini 1.5’s 2 million token capability1.5 Flash is the newest addition to the Gemini model family and the fastest Gemini model served in the API. It’s optimized for high-volume, high-frequency tasks at scale, is more cost-efficient to serve and features our breakthrough long context window.While it’s a lighter weight model than 1.5 Pro, it’s highly capable of multimodal reasoning across vast amounts of information and delivers impressive quality for its size.The new Gemini 1.5 Flash model is optimized for speed and efficiency, is highly capable of multimodal reasoning and features our breakthrough long context window.1.5 Flash excels at summarization, chat applications, image and video captioning, data extraction from long documents and tables, and more. This is because it’s been trained by 1.5 Pro through a process called “distillation,” where the most essential knowledge and skills from a larger model are transferred to a smaller, more efficient model.Read more about 1.5 Flash in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report, on the Gemini technology page, and learn about 1.5 Flash’s availability and pricing.Over the last few months, we’ve significantly improved 1.5 Pro, our best model for general performance across a wide range of tasks.Beyond extending its context window to 2 million tokens, we’ve enhanced its code generation, logical reasoning and planning, multi-turn conversation, and audio and image understanding through data and algorithmic advances. We see strong improvements on public and internal benchmarks for each of these tasks.1.5 Pro can now follow increasingly complex and nuanced instructions, including ones that specify product-level behavior involving role, format and style. We’ve improved control over the model’s responses for specific use cases, like crafting the persona and response style of a chat agent or automating workflows through multiple function calls. And we’ve enabled users to steer model behavior by setting system instructions.We added audio understanding in the Gemini API and Google AI Studio, so 1.5 Pro can now reason across image and audio for videos uploaded in Google AI Studio. And we’re now integrating 1.5 Pro into Google products, including Gemini Advanced and in Workspace apps.Read more about 1.5 Pro in our updated Gemini 1.5 technical report and on the Gemini technology page.Gemini Nano is expanding beyond text-only inputs to include images as well. Starting with Pixel, applications using Gemini Nano with Multimodality will be able to understand the world the way people do — not just through text, but also through sight, sound and spoken language.Read more about Gemini 1.0 Nano on Android.Today, we’re also sharing a series of updates to Gemma, our family of open models built from the same research and technology used to create the Gemini models.We’re announcing Gemma 2, our next generation of open models for responsible AI innovation. Gemma 2 has a new architecture designed for breakthrough performance and efficiency, and will be available in new sizes.The Gemma family is also expanding with PaliGemma, our first vision-language model inspired by PaLI-3. And we’ve upgraded our Responsible Generative AI Toolkit with LLM Comparator for evaluating the quality of model responses.Read more on the Developer blog.As part of Google DeepMind’s mission to build AI responsibly to benefit humanity, we’ve always wanted to develop universal AI agents that can be helpful in everyday life. That’s why today, we’re sharing our progress in building the future of AI assistants with Project Astra (advanced seeing and talking responsive agent).To be truly useful, an agent needs to understand and respond to the complex and dynamic world just like people do — and take in and remember what it sees and hears to understand context and take action. It also needs to be proactive, teachable and personal, so users can talk to it naturally and without lag or delay.While we’ve made incredible progress developing AI systems that can understand multimodal information, getting response time down to something conversational is a difficult engineering challenge. Over the past few years, we’ve been working to improve how our models perceive, reason and converse to make the pace and quality of interaction feel more natural.Building on Gemini, we’ve developed prototype agents that can process information faster by continuously encoding video frames, combining the video and speech input into a timeline of events, and caching this information for efficient recall.By leveraging our leading speech models, we also enhanced how they sound, giving the agents a wider range of intonations. These agents can better understand the context they’re being used in, and respond quickly, in conversation.With technology like this, it’s easy to envision a future where people could have an expert AI assistant by their side, through a phone or glasses. And some of these capabilities are coming to Google products, like the Gemini app and web experience, later this year.We’ve made incredible progress so far with our family of Gemini models, and we’re always striving to advance the state-of-the-art even further. By investing in a relentless production line of innovation, we’re able to explore new ideas at the frontier, while also unlocking the possibility of new and exciting Gemini use cases.Learn more about Gemini and its capabilities. Your information will be used in accordance with Google’s privacy policy.</p> <div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>      Done. Just one step more.
    
      Check your inbox to confirm your subscription.
    You are already subscribed to our newsletter.
    You can also subscribe with a
    different email address
    
    .
    
  Let’s stay in touch. Get the latest news from Google in your inbox.
          Follow Us
</code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kilian-kleemann.info/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[<h3>External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</h3> <p>If you prefer publishing blog posts on medium.com or other external sources, starting version v0.5.0, <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio">al-folio</a> lets you to display your external posts in the blog feed of your website! 🎉🎉</p> <p>Configuring external sources of super simple. After upgrading to v0.5.0, just add the following section to your _config.yml:</p> <pre>external_sources:<br />  - name: medium.com  # name of the source (arbitrary string)<br />    rss_url: <a href="https://medium.com/@al-folio/feed">https://medium.com/@&lt;your-medium-username&gt;/feed</a></pre> <p>The example above adds your medium.com blog post feed as an external source. But you can add arbitrary RSS feeds as sources.</p> <p>Any questions or suggestions? 👉 Start <a href="https://github.com/alshedivat/al-folio/discussions">a discussion on GitHub</a>!</p> <p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;postId=b60a1d241a0a" width="1" height="1" alt=""/></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>